Register of the Christopher Temple Emmet Papers 1913-1974
Hoover Institution Archives
- RADIO BROADCAST PHONOTAPES 1953-1973
  - "The U.N. Debate on Hungary," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 4, 1959
  - "Are Russia and China Drifting Apart?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 17, 1959
  - "Between the Lines," WNTA-TV, January 10, 1960
  - "Anti-Semitic Outbreaks in Germany," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 15, 1960
  - "The Crisis in Algeria," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 29, 1960
  - "Communist Propaganda Techniques," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 12, 1960
  - "How Much Communist Influence in Cuba?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 26, 1960
  - "Should Germany Have Bases in Spain?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 11, 1960
  - "Latest Soviet Offer on Atomic Tests," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 25, 1960
  - "Can de Gaulle Win in Algeria?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, April 8, 1960
  - "De Gaulle: Twenty Years After," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, April 22, 1960
  - Untitled, May 6, 1960
  - "The Plane Incident and the Summit," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 20, 1960
  - "Developments in East Germany," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 3, 1960
  - "Communist Threat in the Caribbean," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 17, 1960
  - "A Reply to Janos Kadar," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 7, 1960
  - "Austria's Place in Foreign Affairs," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 21, 1960
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 16, 1960
  - "The Diplomatic Break with Cuba," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 13, 1961
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 27, 1961
  - "U.N. and the Congo," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 10, 1961
  - "The German Social Democrats and Foreign Policy," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 24, 1961
  - "Where Does the Summit Lead Us?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 16, 1961
  - Untitled, Barry Gray Show, WMCA, August 14, 1961
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 13, 1961 (2 reels)
  - "The Fifth Anniversary of the Hungarian Revolution," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 27, 1961
  - "The Civil War in the Congo," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 10, 1961
  - "Should Communist China be Admitted to the U.N.?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 24, 1961
  - "The Effect of Castro's Communist Confession," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 8, 1961
  - "The U.N. in Crisis," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 22, 1961
  - "Kennedy's First Year," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 5, 1962
  - "The Outlook in Berlin," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 19, 1962
  - "The Cuban Refugees," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 2, 1962
  - "The Dispute over West New Guinea," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 16, 1962 (2 reels) (Box 127)
  - "The U.S. Involvement in South Vietnam," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 2, 1962
  - "Italy's Turn to the Left," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 16, 1962
  - "Britain and the Common Market," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 30, 1962
  - "The Current Debate on the United Nations," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, April 13, 1962
  - "U.S. Partnership with the Common Market," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 11, 1962
  - "The Refugee Tragedy in Hong Kong," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 25, 1962
  - "What Is Our Cold War Policy?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 8, 1962
    Adolf A. Berl, Jr., former assistant secretary of state, and Eugene Lyons, senior editor, "Readers Digest," debate whether the Kennedy policy is a "no win" policy. Mr. Lyons is critical of the administration while Mr. Berle defends its policy. Emmet moderates.
  - "First-Hand Report from Berlin," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, September 28, 1962
    In this season premiere, the guests are Walter Kirschenbaum, assistant commissioner of licenses, New York City, who recently returned from East and West Berlin, and Norbert Muhlen, foreign correspondent and syndicated writer for the North American Newspaper Alliance. Emmet moderates. A short portion of an unrelated program is also on the tape.
  - "Is Our Foreign Policy Sufficiently Dynamic?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 12, 1962
    The guests are Moshe Decter, writer on foreign affairs and former managing editor, "New Leader," and Michael Harrington, author of "The Other America" and editor of "New America." Emmet moderates.
  - "The Prospects for Atlantic Unity," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 26, 1962
    This program about the introduction of the United Kingdom into the Common Market features guests Kurt Birrenbach, member of the Foreign Affairs Committee of the German Parliament, and William Diebold, director of Economic Studies for the Council on Foreign Relations. Emmet moderates.
  - "Impact of Cuba on the Elections," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 9, 1962
  - Untitled, Men's Class of the Air, November 20, 1962
  - "Impact of Cuba on Latin America," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 7, 1962
  - "The U.N. Decision on Hungary," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 21, 1962
  - "Recent Developments in the Congo," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 20, 1963
  - "De Gaulle and the Common Market Crisis," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 1, 1963
  - "Recent Developments in Eastern Europe," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 15, 1963
  - "Should There Be A NATO-Warsaw Non-Aggression Pact?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 1, 1963
  - "Alternatives to Be Faced in Cuba," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 29, 1963
  - "How Great Is Castro's Support in Cuba?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, April 12, 1963
  - "The Dollar Deficit and U.S. Foreign Policy," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, April 26, 1963
  - "Communist Strength in the Italian Elections," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 10, 1963
  - "A New U.S. Policy towards Hungary?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 24, 1963
  - "Should We Restore East-West Trade?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 7, 1963
  - "Consequences of the Communist Wheat Deal," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 1, 1963
  - "Latest Developments in Vietnam," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 15, 1963
  - "Kennedy's Foreign Policy Legacy," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 29, 1963
  - "U.S.-German Relations under President Johnson," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 13, 1963
  - "1963 Balance Sheet of Freedom," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 27, 1963
  - "The Growing Crisis in Southeast Asia: Vietnam," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 10, 1964
  - Untitled, January 15, 1964
  - "Colonialism in Panama: Fact or Myth?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 24, 1964 (2 reels)
  - "De Gaulle and Red China," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 6, 1964
  - "The Crisis in East Africa," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 21, 1964
  - "Recognition of Red China," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 6, 1964
  - "A New U.S. Policy toward Eastern Europe," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 20, 1964
  - "Steps to Save Vietnam," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, April 3, 1964
  - "Is Fulbright Right?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 1, 1964
  - "Are the Captive Nations Still Captive?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 29, 1964
  - "The New Phase of the Berlin Crisis," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 12, 1964
  - "The Big Lie," August 15, 1964
  - Untitled, WEVD, New York, September 25, 1964 (Box 128)
  - "Can We Save Vietnam?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 9, 1964
  - Untitled, October 23, 1964
  - "Can China and Russia Re-Unite?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 6, 1964
  - "Is the Communist Monolith Crumbling?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 20, 1964
  - Untitled, December 4, 1964
  - "The Battle to Save the Pound," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 18, 1964
  - Untitled, January 29, 1965
  - "Germany's Crisis with Nasser and Israel," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 5, 1965
  - "American Foreign Policy and World Opinion," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, April 2, 1965
  - "Initiatives for German Reunification," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, April 16, 1965
  - Sound recording of broadcast April 30, 1965
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002132
    Christopher Emmet interview with Frank Barnett concerning the withdrawal of the United States from Vietnam. Barnett is critical of advertisements in newspapers calling for withdrawal, especially professors who sign these ads even when they do not specialize in international relations nor South East Asia. The men discuss isolationism, non-intervention, and relaxing of tensions in regard to Vietnam and communism in general. Further analyzed is the relationship between public information and the limitations of civil liberties. The interview concludes by discussing the left-right political spectrum and name-calling of fascists, socialists, communists, etc.
  - "Soviet and Chinese Policy on Vietnam," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 14, 1965
  - "Causes of Soviet Anti-Semitism," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 18, 1965 (3 reels)
  - "The New Isolationism," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, July 2, 1965
  - "Crisis in NATO," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 8, 1965 (2 reels)
  - "Revolutionary Changes in Southeast Asia," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 5, 1965
  - "China and the U.N.," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 19, 1965
  - "A Plan for European Renunifcation," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 28, 1966
  - "Our Political Problems in South Vietnam," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 11, 1966
  - "Is German Reunification Possible?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 25, 1966
  - "Is Coalition in Vietnam Possible?" Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 10, 1966
  - "Germany and the U.N.," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, March 24, 1966
  - "The NATO Crisis," April 7, 1966
  - "Developments in the Dominican Republic," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, May 5, 1966
  - Sound recording of broadcast May 19, 1966
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002127
    A three-way conversation with Peter Burley [?]; a candidate for Congress, Harvard Economics professor, and son of the former assistant secretary of state; and John Garrett of the US Information Agency in Vietnam. They discuss various aspects of the Vietnam War
  - "Communist China," June 3, 1966
  - "The Hungarian Revolution: Ten Years After," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 11, 1966
  - "Vietnam," November 8, 1966
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 14, 1967
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 13, 1967
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002159
    Peter White substitutes for Christopher Emmet, interviewing Joseph Buttinger. The men discuss the political history of Vietnam, especially the era of French rule and Vietnamese/Chinese relations.
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, July 12, 1967
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, February 13, 1968
  - Untitled, At Random Show, Chicago, March 23, 1968 (3 reels)
  - Untitled, April 8, 1968 (2 reels)
  - "Unrest in Youth," June 11, 1968
  - Untitled, October 8, 1968 (Box 129)
  - "Can We Save the Universities from Chaos?" WEVD, New York, December 16, 1968
  - "Peru," April 7, 1969
  - "Vietnam," October 7, 1970
  - "India and Pakistan," WEVD, New York, December 2, 1971
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, March 1, 1972
  - "Vietnam," May 3, 1972
  - "China," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 7, 1972
  - "International Drug Traffic," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, October 4, 1972
  - "German Elections," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, November 1, 1972
  - "Will There Be a Bloodbath in Vietnam?" with Daniel Teodoru, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 6, 1972
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002160
    The men discuss whether there will be a future blood bath in Vietnam in the context of America possibly admitting South Vietnamese refugees.
  - "Taiwan," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, January 3, 1973
  - Untitled, WEVD, New York, March 1973
  - "Yugoslavia," WEVD, New York, April 4, 1973
  - Untitled, WEVD, New York, June 1973
  - "Watergate," Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, June 6, 1973
- Incremental materials (Box 130-131)
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1944-1968 (Box 131, reading room workstation)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled records determined to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover
  - 2010 release of records, 1944-1955 (Reading room workstation)
    Letters and report relating to David Martin and the International Rescue Committee. Available as PDF files. The PDF files are page images, so full-text search is not possible.
  - 2011 July release of records, 1950s-1968 (Box 131)
    Letters and resumes relating to David Martin and others. Consists of unclassified records only.
- RADIO BROADCAST PHONORECORDS 1942-1967
  Phonorecords of radio broadcasts, arranged chronologically. Use copies of all phonorecords in this collection are available for immediate access.
  - Untitled (Songs that present Congressman Hamilton Fish in a negative light) undated 2 sides, 78 rpm (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002263
    Includes "The Old Gray Mare" reworked into "Old Man Ham." Possibly from the 1940 election, includes the lyric "20 long years ago." and two songs that may be part of one longer song. The lyrics advocate that all, even Republicans, vote for Fish's opponent.
  - Inga Goegsbro Christensen, "Serenade (To Her Friend Christopher Emmet)" and "Mona (Dedicated to Carl Friedberg)" undated, 2 sides, 78 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002264
    Two songs sung by Louis Birk
  - Private Robert Thomas recording, December 31, 1942, 12 sides
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002259
    Private Robert Thomas speaks about a multi-medium propaganda he'd like to develop entitled, "Uncle Sam's Family." This program would compare experiences of the various ethnic nationalities in Europe to those Americans and European refugees of such decent in the American military. He believes that Europeans will rally behind America when they see that those like them are fighting for democracy and equality to all people. The name was chosen in the idea of that is the most proper description for America, according to Thomas; that America is not a melting pot, but a multicultural nation.
  - "Ireland and the War," People's Platform, WABC, New York March 18, 1944, 6 sides
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002265
    A panel discussion about Ireland in World War II and fascism in Ireland. Missing two of the three discs or parts 1, 2, 4, and 5
  - Is Disarmament Possible Now? Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York January 7, 1947, 6 sides, 78 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002267
    Guests are Norman Thomas of the Socialist Party and Colonel Truman Smith
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York, December 23, 1949, 8 sides, 78 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002422
    Emmet and two German guests discuss the possibility of a nationalist resurgence, anti-Semitism, and communism in Germany. They analyze both the guests' empirical evidence and macro statistical evidence such as the amount of former Nazi Party members in government and other topics.
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York November 26, 1950, 8 sides, 78 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002423
    Emmet and labor attorney Louis Waldman discuss if communist China should be recognized and admitted to the United Nations. His guest is a staunch anti-communist and offers several arguments for why communist China should not be recognized.
  - Untitled, Barry Gray Show, WMCA December 9, 1963, 2 sides 33 1/3 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002260
    Brutus Coste, Edmund Gasper, and Christopher Emmet (all of the Assembly of Captive European Nations) appear on the Barry Gray Show to discuss Soviet occupation of and influence in Hungary.
  - "Protest" March 12, 1964, 3 sides, 33 1/3 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002262
    The NBC program is a debate between Gordon Zahn, author of In Solitary Witness: The Life and Death of Franz Jägerstätter, and Christopher Emmet, representing the American Council on Germany. The men debate the accuracy of the play "The Deputy" and if Pope Pius could be considered a criminal for his acquiescence of the holocaust. The men mention both good and bad things the Pope did during the war.
  - Untitled, Foreign Affairs Round Table, WEVD, New York March 20, 1964, 2 sides, 33 1/3 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002425
    Christopher Emmet and Professor Brzezinski discuss if America should treat other communist nations as it does Poland and Yugoslavia.
  - Untitled, Sandy Lesberg Show, WOR January 6, 1967, 4 sides, 33 1/3 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002426
    A panel discussion about Nazism and communism in Germany. Guests include Brutus Costa, Matthew [?], Christopher Emmet, Henry Marx, and Walter Strauss
  - Untitled, Barry Gray Show, WMCA March 10, 1967, 4 sides, 33 1/3 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002427
    Contains a panel discussing an article concerning Germany in Look Magazine. The panel analyzes the current nationalist tendencies in the NPD and if these will grow into a movement similar to the Nazis. Panelists are Joaquin Prince (spelling uncertain), Ted Hutus (spelling uncertain), and Christopher Emmet. The audio sounds like it may have been recorded off the airwaves.
  - Untitled, Barry Farber Show, WOR June 23, 1967, 5 sides, 33 1/3 rpm
    Use copy reference number: 74105_a_0002428
    A panel discussion on the summit at Glassboro, New Jersey between Lyndon Johnson and Alexey Kosygin, the war in Vietnam, and Israel. Guests are U.S. Representative Leonard Farbstein, National Review publisher William Rusher, Christopher Emmet, and Allard K. Lowenstein.
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1941-1968, 88 prints, 1 negative / 9 envelopes (Box 74105 - 10.A-V)
  Photographs, arranged by subject.
  - 2 publicity prints used by the Committee to Aid Britain by Reciprocal Trade, circa 1940-41 (Folder A)
  - 5 prints of General Draza Mihailovic and Chetnik troops in Yugoslavia, 1944; 12 prints of scenes at hearings of the Commission of Inquiry sponsored by the Committee for a Fair Trial for Draja Mihailovich, 1946; 1 negative of newspaper clippings relating to the trial of Draza Mihailovic. (Folder B)
  - 35 prints of atrocities in the Greek Civil War., undated (Folder C)
  - 10 prints of Christopher T. Emmet and other participants in the American Friends of the Captive Nations Liberation Rally in New York City., May 25, 1956 (Folder D)
  - 6 prints of Christopher T. Emmet and other participants in the American Friends of the Captive European Nations plenary meeting., June 28, 1957 (Folder E)
  - 4 prints of the ex-wife and children of General Pal Maleter, a leader of the Hungarian Revolutions, at a New York press conference held to appeal for his release., September 10, 1957. (Folder F)
  - 4 prints of ceremonies in observation of Captive Nations Week in the U.S., 1961 (Folder G)
  - 2 prints of Christopher T. Emmet and other participants in a ceremony observing Captive Nations Week at New York City Hall., July 19, 1967. (Folder H)
  - 8 miscellaneous prints, undated (Folder I)